Kel Strother

Software Developer

Denver, CO | kelstrother@gmail.com | (303) 842-7778 | Portfolio | linkedin.com/in/kelstrother

SUMMARY

I am a full stack software engineer with a focus on front end development. I put forth my knowledge of JavaScript and front-end frameworks like Vue.js and React to build efficient products that are both fast and responsive. My background as a traveling musician has taught me to embrace being outside of my comfort zone while still exceeding expectations. I plan to utilize these past and present experiences along with an eye for design to build things that adapt to the ever-evolving state of web development.

SKILLS

Front End: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Vue.js, React, SASS, Jquery, SCSS

Back End: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Node.js **Design:** Affinity Designer, Affinity Photo, Photoshop, Illustrator, AdobeXD, Figma

PROJECTS

<u>Vuezic</u> (Vue.js, Firebase)

A platform for users to collaboratively build playlists for any occasion.

- Used this project as an opportunity to learn Vue.js
- o Experience with user authentication
- o Built functionality for users to upload image and audio files
- o Continuing the process of audio streaming functionality

<u>Gimme.it</u> (React, Express, Mongoose, MongoDB)

Full stack web app allowing users to browse through a catalog of donated items.

- o Gained experience developing with a team
- o Full CRUD functionality
- Authenticated users can post items on the app
- All users can claim any item available.

<u>Time Piece</u> (HTML/CSS, JavaScript)

A clock that functions based on the user's current timezone

o Gained experience manipulating date and time aspects of the DOM

Light The Way (HTML/CSS, JavaScript)

Visually appealing project that displays light trails based on mouse movement

- o Practice working with mouse events in JavaScript
- Expanded my knowledge of DOM manipulation with JS and CSS

EXPERIENCE

Palace Arms at The Brown Palace Hotel, Fine Dining Captain Feb 2015 - Mar 2020

- o Received extensive fine dining education
- Gained experience in multiple hospitality outlets
- o Further expanded wine knowledge

Balestreri Vinyards, Head Waiter

Jan 2014 - Feb 2015

- Oversaw the managements of banquet events
- Continued wine education

Ondo's Tapas Bar, Manager/Barkeep

Sep 2012 - Nov 2014

- o Developed widespread knowledge of running and maintaining a restaurant.
- Continued wine education

EDUCATION

General Assembly, Software Engineering Certificate

Dec 2020 - March 2021